The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Outer Suzaku Tomb
The Suzaku Tomb isn’t large,
it's divided into the inner and outer tomb.
A single sweep of Divine Sense
should help you find an altar.
Pass through it to enter the inner tomb.
There is a mountain at the center,
that is Ye Wuyou’s tomb.
Will you...
play with me ?
A monster ?
No.
It seems that the fire element of this place
manifested as a fire spirit.
As expected,
the scorched earth of this place
will endlessly heal this thing.
Will you...
play with me !?
Break !
This is
a soul strand ?
Every grain of this scorched earth
is actually a soul strand.
These soul strands are weak,
so they must be mortals.
Situ said the soul strands are in the inner tomb.
So why are they here ?
Could it be
that my soul strand is also one of these spirits ?
3 days later
3 days
and still no trace of the altar.
Senior !
Senior, save me !
If you help me
I can tell you
how to enter the inner tomb !
Junior's name is Murong Yun.
Thank you, seniors, for saving me.
Mo Yunhai
Early stage Soul Transformation
This old man is Mo Yunhai.
Fellow cultivator,
you're really skilled.
Junior,
you said that
you know how to enter the inner tomb.
Senior Mo,
when I arrived here
I saw Qian Feng
with several Forsaken Immortal Clan Warriors
enter the inner tomb.
If not for my low cultivation,
I'd have entered too.
I wonder where they entered.
At an altar.
But it's very remote
and the entrance has complex restrictions.
With all these strange things nearby,
I couldn't enter it alone.
If you can promise
to take me in with you,
then Junior
will lead you both there.
Fellow cultivator,
it should be manageable
if we join forces.
What do you think ?
This is the place !
Is this altar
the one you mentioned ?
That central spot
is the entrance.
Soul Search !
He's not lying.
However,
only one person can enter successfully.
I confirm it's here.
Fellow cultivator,
I'll go first.
You're quite clever.
How did you notice ?
I can tell you
but you'll have to answer my questions first.
Interesting...
But you answer me first !
Your clothes are ancient,
modern cultivators don't wear those.
Just this was enough ?
Of course, there are other reasons.
Now you tell me.
Who
are you ?
I'm formed from soul strands.
Why are you here ?
When this place shattered,
soul strands scattered everywhere.
Your soul strand might be nearby,
right over there.
What's your objective ?
I have no particular purpose.
I just don't want people to succeed.
Your turn now.
What gave me out ?
The spiritual energy in those lightning bolts
was enough to kill you instantly
but they just kept following you.
Your self-centered act was too fake.
Tell me,
where is the real altar ?
You'll never know !
Seal !
Even if you kill these soul strands,
it's people of planet Suzaku that will die.
But I
can absorb new soul strands to revive.
You can't kill me !
I won't kill you,
but I will seal you.
You will be cut off from the outside.
When your host's lifespan ends,
you
will also die.
I'll tell you where the altar is !
Now let me out !
Speak.
East of here
in a valley surrounded by 9 peaks.
The mist there is white instead of black.
The altar is at the bottom.
You liar !
As more cultivators
discovered the secret of the soul strands,
they started slaughtering them repeatedly,
waiting for their own soul strand to appear.
This cruel method was sacrificing the lives of others
to find their own soul strand.
This made the situation in the Suzaku Tomb
even more chaotic.
It should have recovered by now,
lure it out again.
Still no sign of my soul strand !
Explode !
He...
He's dead...
His soul strand was destroyed.
Again !
We're waiting here for my soul strand.
If it doesn't appear,
then each time it reforms
we kill the spirit.
Outer Suzaku Tomb Altar
Long time no see,
Wang Lin...
Scram !
You really are Early stage Soul Transformation...
Your progress is astonishing.
Zhuque Zi's death is imminent.
Our battle
is unnecessary.
I don't just fight you
because my master told me to.
It's for your Thousand Illusions Ruthless Domain.
Am I right ?
I use illusions
to experience mortal emotions
and cultivate ruthlessness.
While you
started with emotions
to comprehend Life and Death.
By becoming mortal
you understood the Dao of Life and Death !
You and I
are the same.
I don't have time for this
but Liu Mei is Middle stage Soul Transformation
so I can't end this quickly...
I must get my soul strand as fast as possible.
If you dare to use the Billion-Soul Flag,
I'll just destroy this altar.
It will take days to reform
and you can't wait that long...
What do you really want ?
I just need one last illusion to complete my domain
and reach Late stage Soul Transformation.
I will borrow your Dao
to complete my Thousand Illusions.
What do you think ?
Just one illusion ?
I'll show you,
just don't regret it later.
My Thousand Illusions Ruthless Domain
is like a peacock's thousand feathers.
Each feather
is an illusion.
Each illusion
is one of my avatar's lifetimes.
Now that only the last one remains
You...
will become my cauldron !
Red Butterfly's Ruthless Domain
required severing love.
But this woman is so cold-hearted
that she has no love to sever.
Her domain
is far above Red Butterfly's.
The beauty of this world
resides in its ruthlessness.
The beauty of a rainbow
is admired by millions
but cannot be captured.
Like the tail of a peacock,
even if it's beautiful,
it can rarely be seen.
Ruthless...
I thought that your domain
was aligned with the law of the heavens.
Our paths diverge but we share the same ruthlessness.
I never expected your domain to have such a glaring flaw.
It makes devouring your domain easy.
It's almost a bit disappointing.
Devour !
Who cares about the law of the heavens ?
Between heaven and earth,
what must die will die
even if the law of the heavens allow the opposite.
I don't agree with that.
Your last illusion
will not be my domain.
Life and Death Reincarnation cycle !
I really like this physical body
that you have found for me.
Brother Wang,
this is how much I understood of Liu Mei's domain.
She only needs one last illusion
to reach a thousand.
Brother Wang, you must be careful.
If Liu Mei really wants to devour my domain,
then I'm no match for her with my cultivation.
There is only one way
to break her Dao Heart.
Little brother,
you finally remembered me.
I think you need a new body.
I'll help you get one
and give you back your freedom.
Lust is the perfect counter to Liu Mei's Ruthlessness.
Once Mei Ji takes over,
Liu Mei will lose her mind
and become Mei Ji's puppet.
Wang Lin...
you bastard !
If you hadn't insisted on devouring my domain,
I wouldn't have had the chance to let Mei Ji possess you.
You brought
all this upon yourself !
Seal !
The Thousand Illusions Ruthless Domain
will be stained by lust
breaking its ruthlessness.
Formation,
activate !
Little sister,
will you obediently give me your physical body ?
What's wrong ?
A part of my domain
is about to possess a body.
Is that your old
Lust Domain ?
If the possession succeeds
she will take a part of my power.
I can't allow this.
I need to wipe her out today.
How can there be a force interrupting the possession !?
She wants to get rid of me !
Activate !
Since neither can take over the body
then we will merge !
I didn't expect
that my final illusion
would be one of lust.
Wang Lin,
you have ruined my Dao Heart
by transforming my domain into the Thousand Illusions Lust Domain !
This grudge between us
is irreconcilable !
Mountain River
Suzaku Tomb
According to Situ,
there should be a mountain in the center of the inner tomb.
The crystal should be there.
I think that in order to find the center,
I need to cross this ravine.
The soul strands here
are getting stronger.
I'd rather not provoke them.
Shit !
The tomb's collapse is accelerating !
The scene was already cryptic in the novel, it's even more confusing in the donghua. It will get explained later anyways. Feel free to read what happened in the novel and try to read between the lines:
Her domain was currently far above Wang Lin’s Life and Death Domain, which was only at the Early stage of Soul Transformation, so he obviously couldn’t resist it.
The pink mist that covered everything within tens of thousands of kilometers was now slowly condensing back toward the valley.
This process lasted for two days. All of the pink mist outside of the valley had come back, but the valley itself was still covered in pink mist. From inside the mist, the painful cries of a woman could be heard, but that voice was also filled with pleasure. The voice was like the song of a fairy that would make anyone’s heart pound and blood surge.
After an unknown amount of time, the pink mist gradually faded, revealing a woman lying on the side of the altar. Clarity slowly returned to her eyes.
[...]
“I can’t believe that the last illusion of the Thousand Illusion Ruthless Domain is this illusion. The moment this illusion appears, the domain changes to the Thousand Illusion Lust Domain. All of this is like an illusion, yet it is so real. I never thought that my Thousand Illusion Ruthless Domain’s last illusion would be obtained like this… Master wanted me to leave my mark on Wang Lin’s dao heart, but he never would have thought that my last illusion would contain his aura…”
Wang Lin’s body appeared in a wasteland in the inner section of the Suzaku Tomb. After he appeared, he looked into the sky with a very complex expression.
While being surrounded by the pink mist, he felt like he was in a dream. When the pink mist dissipated, he saw a woman below him. At that moment, his heart felt pain for her.
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.